*
(upbeat theme music playing)
Good evening,
and welcome to "Montague."
I'm your host,
Franklin Montague.
And today we're gonna
take a look
at the growing outlook
of accepted sexuality
and its effects
on black youth and culture.
With us today, we have
the Head of the Center
of Trans-American Issues,
Dr. Debra Holt,
and recording artist
Paper Boi.
Good evening to you both.
-Good evening, Montague.
-'Sup?
Uh, let's start
at the beginning.
Paper Boi, last Tuesday
you engaged in a Twitter rant
that had some pretty
inflammatory statements.
But the one statement
that seems to have made
-the biggest impact...
-(sighs)
Was this one and I quote,
"Y'all the..."
N-words "who said I was weird
for not wanting to"
F-word "Caitlyn Jenner."
Would you want to, uh,
explain that statement?
No.
Well, could you
explain that statement?
(blows)
I...
meant what I said.
You don't think
your tweets are transphobic?
I just don't have to
have sex
with Caitlyn Jenner
'cause y'all say so.
Mm.
So you don't think
-Caitlyn Jenner's important?
-(tsks)
Look, I get what
y'all saying, right?
But she's not
super important to me,
like, not my life.
So how long
have you disliked transpeople?
Man, look,
I just found out they exist,
-to be honest.
-I--No, no--
"I make her switch sides,
Caitlyn Jenner in reverse"?
Is that not a--
a lyric of yours?
Man, I was just rapping, man.
Look, I've said worse things.
You ever heard my song,
"Illuminati Sex"?
-Haven't heard it yet.
-Well, there we go then.
Debra, you've written
about this current phenomenon
in your book,
Transition:
Gender in a New Generation.
What do you think
about all this?
I look at these statements as
natural consequences
of a culture
-of exclusion and power.
-Mm.
You know, there's--
there's a large swath of...
-(scoffs)
-Gender and sexuality roles
that are just being exposed to
a large portion of the public.
(chuckling)
DEBRA: Uh, it's harder
for certain sections
to deal with this transition
uh, because of conflict
of interest,
and, frankly, identity issues.
In this case,
the rap community.
Now, I truly believe
it's, uh,
has more to do with issues
of masculinity
in the black community
than actual
homophobia or--or transphobia.
-Please explain.
-Yes, please, please.
Tell me--
tell me about myself.
Go on.
Well, Mis--Mister, uh, Pa--
Mr. Paper Boi--
Mister, yeah.
What would you
consider yourself?
A rapper?
A straight rapper?
Hell yeah.
Well, I did some research
on your lyrics,
and they're actually
very pro sexual-spectrum.
-Oh?
-Pro-what?
"If I eff with you,
you my N-word,
you my N-word for life."
Yo, you know
that ain't what I meant.
Yeah, oh, I understand,
but, you know,
there's a layer of fluidity...
No, no, no.
There's no extra layer.
DEBRA: That you yourself
don't even realize.
I don't think about
what I'm rapping half the time.
Look, I'm just trying
to get paid,
you feel me?
Look, (bleep),
why you think
I'm on this show?
You're not
getting paid for this.
Hey--
Hey, Earn--man?
Black men aren't ready
to accept the implications
of a trans-accepting culture.
No--look, I'm allowed
to say that it's weird.
"It"?
No, look, I'm not
calling him a "it."
-Naw, I'm just saying that--
-"Him"?
Look--look, can I say something?
Damn!
FRANKLIN: All right.
-Well, it depends.
-I was trying to say--
-We got to take a break.
When we're back,
we're gonna take a look
into a young boy's struggle
for equality.
(theme music playing)
(sighs)
(theme music)
(sportscaster on phone)
(front entrance dings)
(Muzak plays in background)
*
(sportscasters continue)
(beep)
$1.49?
But the price
on the can, though.
The price
is on the can, though.
(crowd cheers on phone)
(sportscasters continue)
(jazzy lounge music)
*
(music continues)
(upbeat hip-hop instrumental
music)
*
MAN: The Dodge Charger.
Make a statement without
saying anything at all.
(theme music playing)
Earlier in our show,
we talked about
transitions in sexuality.
Uh, but what about race?
Our correspondent,
Nathan Wielder,
has the story.
Harrison looks from the outside
to be your average teenager.
He goes to school,
plays video games,
even listens to music
in his room.
But there's one difference.
I'm a 35-year-old white man.
NATHAN: Harrison,
born Antwoine Smalls,
has trans-racial identity,
identifying as Harrison Booth,
a 35-year-old white man
from Colorado.
And when did you know
that you were a
35-year-old white man?
Well, I've always
felt different.
I go to the store,
the movies,
and just be thinking
to myself, like,
"Why am I not getting
the respect I deserve?"
And then,
it just hit me.
I'm white...
and 35.
I just miss Colorado sometimes,
you know.
Here, I pretend the buildings
are the old
San Juan Mountain ranges but,
you know, the jobs is here.
And where do you work?
I'm a Systems Engineer
for Coca-Cola.
Oh. Okay.
That boy don't work.
He go to school,
and that's it.
-Mm-hmm.
-One day, he said,
"Call me Harrison."
I said, "Who's that?"
He said, "Me."
Do you believe
that he is a white man?
I mean, he isn't.
(bleep), I'd love
to wake up one day and say,
"Hey, everybody,
I'm Rihanna."
But I ain't.
It's been pretty hard.
My family just doesn't get it.
You know, I try to get them
to go out with me,
go on walks,
go to the farmers market,
chat with people,
but...yeah.
So why don't you think
that they get it?
I don't think
they get it because
they don't realize that race
is just a made-up thing.
Mm-hmm.
They grew up
having labels, and me,
I'm just--I'm just
not like that.
I see.
So how do you embrace
your identity?
-I dress a certain way.
-Ah.
Patagonia.
I wear a thick,
brown leather belt.
I like to envision myself
after the surgery.
(clears throat)
"Hey, excuse me,
what IPA do you have on tap?"
"Hey, did you see
Game of Thrones last night?"
Yeah.
So your--
your surgery,
that's later this year?
Right.
I started working
at Stonecrest Mall,
so hopefully
by then I have enough money
to take the next step.
Mm-hmm.
So you work at Coca-Cola
and the mall?
Right.
Correct, I work at both.
NATHAN: Harrison
has been planning
a full racial transition
with a Dr. Samuel Vergara
who guarantees Harrison
can visually transition
through an experimental
procedure
that will allow Harrison
not only to be a white man
but whatever race he chooses.
The procedure's
absolutely 100% possible.
He's gonna look weird though.
NATHAN: But before Harrison
can fully realize
his physical identity,
he still has the day-to-day
that's filled with
discrimination and ridicule.
It--it's pretty awful,
you know.
You--you walk
in the streets,
and black people, they see you,
they nod to you like,
"Hey, good to see us."
And it's to the point
where I've just given up.
I've stopped trying
to convince them
-that I'm not "us."
-Gotcha.
Hey, excuse me,
this is definitely the guy.
He doesn't even live
in the area.
I've never seen him before.
(police radio chatter)
*
HARRISON: I think
we're taking slow strides,
but you have to believe
things are getting better,
otherwise,
you'll just die inside.
Is there anything
you'd like to say to
other black kids out there
who may be going through
the same thing?
Just be you.
At all costs.
But also,
stop dressing so crazy.
Hmm.
(gentle instrumental music)
*
(guitar music flourishes)
Absolutely.
Hi.
I'm Devyonne Johnson,
famous movie star.
When the director calls cut
and I get a quick five,
you know I'm reaching
for the smooth taste
of Swisher Sweets.
Swisher Sweets are the only
cigarillos made with
the highest quality tobacco
from family-owned farms.
It's their high standards
and experience
that make for a quality smoke
you can enjoy every time.
(sniffs)
(click)
*
(blows)
Yeah...
(chuckles)
I only smoke Swisher Sweets.
It's the smooth taste.
These Swisher Sweets
is good as hell.
Here, make sure
this one's empty.
Swisher Sweets.
There's just
something about 'em.
And try our new pre-dumps
Swisher Sweets as well.
(mellow jazz music)
*
(theme music playing)
And we're back.
And today we're talking about
transitions with my guests,
Atlanta rapper Paper Boi
and Dr. Debra Holt.
Ah, Paper Boi, are you afraid
to speak your mind
on this subject?
Actually, yup, I am.
You can't say real (bleep)
anymore without somebody
trying to make sure
you never make money forever.
FRANKLIN: So you think
you're being persecuted?
Yes, I am.
Man, you can't even say
"ho" in a song no more.
(scoffs)
A travesty, I'm sure.
-(chuckles)
ALFRED: Yo, why you--
Yo, why you talk
like that?
Like, "a travesty, I'm sur--"
like, what?
You're--you're whining
about chickens
-coming home to roost.
-No-no-no-no-no.
Rap is chickens
coming home to roost.
Look, my life is messed up
from (bleep) y'all did, okay?
That's black news.
You can look that up.
Well, your news
is problematic.
-Bitch, that ain't my fault!
-Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I won't have you on my show
calling anyone "bitches."
How you gonna blame me
for news being bad, huh?
FRANKLIN: All right,
simmer down, simmer down.
You can't even have
an intelligent dialogue
-without spewing profanities.
-(groans)
-It's--it's ludicrous.
FRANKLIN: Okay, okay, okay.
Paper Boi,
isn't a lack of a father
the reason you hate transpeople?
What?
Lack of a father?
Man, you hear yourself?
(bleep), shut up.
Man, here's the thing.
Man, I--
it's hard for me to care
about this when nobody
cares about me
as a black human man,
you feel me?
Like, Caitlyn Jenner
is just doing
what rich white men been doing
since the dawn of time,
which is whatever
the hell he want.
So why should I care?
What make him so special?
But--but as a black man
in this country,
shouldn't you care about
the civil liberties of others,
since they're
so closely related to--to
your struggle for equality?
What you talking 'bout?
I do care.
Look, I don't have a problem
with gay people, transpeople,
because that's tolerance,
but where's tolerance
for people like me?
You know what I'm saying?
Like...
(sighs) Look.
I should be able
to say something is weird
without people hating on me.
All right?
Look, I never--
I never said anything
about taking away
nobody's rights.
A'ight? Never.
I--I understand
what you're saying,
but--but some people
found your remarks offensive.
Yeah, well,
freedom of speech, (bleep).
No, you're right.
I agree.
But your music is detrimental
to black teens.
(scoffs) Yeah, but so is
all rap music, right?
-I mean, and rock music...
-Rock.
Before it was
taken over by rap.
Yeah, I agree.
You hate... women!
(bleep), what?
(theme music playing)
Questions.
The universe.
Paternity tests?
Salutations.
(gentle music)
Hi.
My name is Ahmad White.
You may know me
from your dreams.
Call this number below
and get the answers
you deserve.
(upbeat music)
When I called Ahmad White,
I was three months behind
on my car note.
(scoffs) My stepson,
he was in jail.
My life was in shambles!
But now, I got a truck,
I got a girlfriend,
I got the answers I deserve.
Thank you, Ahmad White.
Most people don't realize
their chakra's
in another universe.
Don't be dumb.
Call now.
Me and Ahmad found out
I was a moon sign,
and I wasn't getting enough
crystal in my diet.
Now, I live
in a beautiful home.
Ahmad gave me the answers
I was looking for.
Come to our Liberty Center
and get a free juice
and Nutella sandwich.
When I called Ahmad,
my life was going nowhere fast.
After a Nutella sandwich
and juice,
my life's a lot better.
(upbeat tone sustained)
Open your third eye.
He works.
He just works.
He really works.
He works.
He really, really works.
Knowledge is the path
to greatness.
If you'd like to be
smart as a baby dolphin,
call now.
(ethereal music)
(upbeat hip-hop instrumental
music)
*
(engine revs)
That's a nice car.
You know him?
That's Victor Wallace.
His wife left him
for his brother.
Long court battle.
Kids, house--
It got messy.
He ain't say one word
the whole trial.
But then at the end,
he just stood up and said,
"Leave me my Dodge Charger."
He been driving around
this neighborhood
in circles for a week.
-Just waving.
-Mm.
Nice car though.
(nozzle fumbling)
(upbeat hip-hop instrumental
music)
*
(tires screech)
MAN: The Dodge Charger.
Keep it in the divorce.
(gasps)
King Coco's Crunch-O's.
The legend is true!
(creaking)
Gimme that crunch!
No!
(grunts)
Nice try.
But only kids can have...
all: Coconut Crunch-O's.
WOLF: That chocolatey
coconut crunch
in every bite.
(crunches)
Oh, I can almost taste it!
Bbbbbb!
(train horn whistles)
Oh, I got to have
them Crunch-O's!
-(grunts)
-Ow! Ow!
Man!
Ow!
-Stop resisting.
-(pained groans)
-Stop resisting, sir.
-(pained struggle) Damn!
-Stop...resisting.
-Shit, man!
Oh! Mother--
(grunts)
Stay down.
(handcuffs click)
What happened?
He's going to jail.
That's what happened.
This is some bullshit!
You all right?
He's fine.
He just doesn't wanna
go to jail.
You sitting on my back, man!
(bones crack)
Ah!
Sir, be quiet.
Yo!
You sitting on his back!
He was trying
to steal your cereal, right?
I mean,
it's just cereal.
He can have it!
Man, I'm just hungry, man!
They don't let wolves
in stores, man!
Step back, guys.
I'm going to
lift the offender up.
We are now going
to our feet, sir.
Let's go, sir, let's go.
Nigga, I could be
eating these kids!
But I'm out here
eating cereal!
Hey, it's cool!
We'll just give him
the cereal.
No, only kids
can have Coconut Crunch-O's.
You know that.
(tsks)
That's a wack law.
This fool know he eat
Coconut Crunch-O's,
and you ain't no kid!
Let me do my job.
I said back up...sir!
(brooding dramatic music)
(crunches)
MAN: Coconut Crunch-O's
is a part of
this balanced breakfast.
(theme music playing)
Earlier we showed a clip
about a young man
dealing with trans-racial
identity.
Well, we've got him joining us
via Facebook video chat.
Please welcome
Antwoine Smalls to the show.
Hello, Montague, thank you
for having me on your show.
-So now, Antwoine...
ALFRED: (laughs)
-It's Harrison.
-I'm sorry.
-Harrison.
-(chuckling)
FRANKLIN: How's your life been
since we last saw you?
ALFRED: Ohh...
It's pretty good.
I just came back
from Charleston, South Carolina.
FRANKLIN: Ah.
-Beautiful.
I was checking out
some cheap art spaces
for me and a friend
that I made, uh--
What--wait--
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Yo. This is dumb.
-Like, that--this is dumb.
DEBRA: What--
ALFRED: Like, dude, wait, wait.
Did you power up?
'Cause you look like
Super Saiyan right now.
Like, is that, like,
is that the Goku...
FRANKLIN: (sighs)
-Like Dragon Ball collection,
my (bleep), like?
You look like
-a fake Ellen DeGeneres.
-This is just...
-Like a Felon DeGeneres.
-Okay.
Look, no-no-no, you look
like Drake Malfoy, dude, like.
Bangs, my (bleep)?
Like, nobody told you
-not to do bangs--Like--
FRANKLIN: Okay, okay.
-Nice tolerance.
FRANKLIN: Mr. Boi.
ALFRED: What is up--Wait, wait--
-Okay, okay, thank you.
-None of y'all? Okay.
FRANKLIN: Thank you.
-That is very inappropriate.
-Sorry, man, go ahead.
-Shh.
-It's--it's okay.
Sadly, the black community,
they just aren't accepting
of racial diversity or
anyone different,
for that matter.
-Mm. Now, Harrison...
ALFRED: (groans)
Would you say that, uh,
the--the rap game
or the hip-hop community
is especially intolerant
of the lifestyle you chose?
We really can't blame rap
or the hip-hop culture.
He's just expressing himself
to the best of his ability.
And I will defend
his right to do that.
He's telling a story, or, like,
views from the streets.
-You know, like a ghetto news.
-Mm.
-Okay. (snickers)
-But--but Harrison,
don't you think
that the rap community
and its treatment of transpeople
and homosexuals
is indicative of a larger
problem in the black community,
one that makes
your lifestyle unacceptable?
No, no way.
Not at all.
I mean, a man wanting
to turn himself into a woman--
that's just unnatural,
and I don't think
we should have our kids
thinking that that's okay.
So I will support that message.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-What are you saying?
-(stifled laugh)
I'm not into gay marriage.
That--that is gross.
Why would I ever tolerate
something like that?
Marriage is meant for
a man and a woman,
not that--
that's an abomination.
We're--We--No.
How can you say that
with the discrimination
you were just talking about?
-I mean, how--
-It's the truth.
-What are you, crazy?
-This (bleep) crazy!
That is all the time
we have tonight.
-I'd like to thank my guests...
ALFRED: Oh, my God.
-Dr. Holt, Paper Boi.
ALFRED: (chuckling)
Please check for her book
Transition,
as well as
Paper Boi's mixtape Postal.
ALFRED: Yup!
-Available...
wherever mixtapes
are available.
-Good night.
ALFRED: (laughing)
Like, you look
like a dying palm tree.
Right? Like you look like
the lost fifth Beatle,
my (bleep), that they just
don't talk about.
That, like, power up,
like--
they gave him (bleep) bangs,
like--(laughing).
DEBRA: I don't care for it.
(theme music playing)
*
(dramatic music)
(low sustained tone)